<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>syllabi | PSY 503: Psych Statistics</title>
    <link>/syllabus/</link>
      <atom:link href="/syllabus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>syllabi</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/cogsciimage.jpeg</url>
      <title>syllabi</title>
      <link>/syllabus/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem Sets</title>
      <link>/syllabus/dda/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/syllabus/dda/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;There will roughly 10 problem sets over the course of the semester that will involve applying what you learned in class and practicing your R skills and analyzing a set of data and interpreting the findings. You may work together and/or
consult one another when analyzing the data but you must work alone when writing the
report&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project</title>
      <link>/syllabus/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/syllabus/project/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Your semester project assignment is due at the end of the semester and is submitted as a link on Canvas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will discuss this project across the semester. As an overview, you will be demonstrating that you can conduct a reproducible analysis, which is an analysis of data that is independently verifiable. For example, someone else could obtain your data and code and independently reproduce your analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will complete three related parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reproducible Report: Obtain open-data from an existing psych paper, load the data in R, and attempt to reproduce the statistical analysis that the original authors reported. If you have your own data you would like to analyze you can use this to&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;APA paper: Learn how to use the &lt;code&gt;papaja&lt;/code&gt; package that allows you to compile .Rmd files to APA style manuscripts in pdf form. Then, write a short APA-style research report that describes your reproducible analysis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simulation based power analysis: Include a simulation based power analysis at the end of your APA paper.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;part-1-reproducible-report-10-points&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Part 1: Reproducible report (10 points)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;finding-a-paper-with-data&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Finding a paper with data&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few tips for finding a psych paper with open data. &lt;strong&gt;Most important&lt;/strong&gt;, for this assignment you do not need to re-analyze &lt;strong&gt;all of the data&lt;/strong&gt; from a particular paper. Many papers have multiple experiments, and multiple analyses, including analyses you may not be familiar with. You can restrict your re-analysis to a portion of the paper. For example, you might only re-analyze the results from one experiment, and perhaps only the results relevant to one of the tests reported for the experiment. &lt;strong&gt;You can limit your re-analyses to tests that have been covered in lecture or lab&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io&#34;&gt;https://osf.io&lt;/a&gt; The open science framework contains many repositories of open data that are part of published papers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some journals, including Psychological Science, put badges on papers with open data. Look for the blue open-data badge. You will usually find the link to the open-data in the paper.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;loading-the-data-into-r&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Loading the data into R&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data you find could be in many different formats. It should be possible to load it into R and transform the data into the format/organization that you need to complete the analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;re-analysis-of-original-data&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Re-analysis of original data&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Focus on a single analysis that was relevant to one of the research questions. For example, if the analysis involved several t-tests:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conduct and report the same t-tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Report a table of means&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Report a graph of the means&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;write-a-reproducible-report&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Write a reproducible report&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of a reproducible report is that someone else could exactly reproduce your analysis given your report. It is easy to make reproducible reports using R markdown. If you write your report in an .Rmd file, and that file includes your scripts for loading and analyzing the data, then by sharing your .rmd file, other people can exactly reproduce your report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your report should include the following (the points add up to 10 for part 1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A brief description of the research question and experiment (with citation to the paper, and link to find the data) (3 points)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The R code chunks necessary to complete the re-analysis (3 points).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A write-up of your re-analysis results. (3 points)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A brief discussion of whether you were successful or not. (1 point)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*If you would like to run an additional analysis (not included in paper), also include a write-up of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;part-2-apa-paper-in-r-markdown-10-points&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Part 2: APA paper in R markdown (10 points)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;papaja&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Papaja&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In part 2, you will learn how to use the &lt;code&gt;papaja&lt;/code&gt; package to create APA style manuscripts using R markdown. We will discuss how to use &lt;code&gt;papaja&lt;/code&gt; in class. You will create a new .rmd file using the papaja template, and then transfer your reproducible report into this format. You will write very brief sections for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;abstract (50-100 words) (1 point)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;introduction (1 or two paragraphs) (1 point)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;methods (1 paragraph) (1 point)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;results (Your re-analysis results) (3 point)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;must include the R code chunks for the analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;full points only if the reporting of results is also reproducible (not by hand), as in the the example (see below).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34; style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;discussion (very brief, 1 paragraph) (1 point)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;references (cite the paper, and anything else you want to cite) (1 point)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A completed .Rmd file and successfully compiled .pdf using &lt;code&gt;papaja&lt;/code&gt; (2 points)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, the purpose here is not to write a full-length APA paper, but to get some experience with using the &lt;code&gt;papaja&lt;/code&gt; package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;part-3-power-analysis-10-points&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Part 3: Power analysis (10 points)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;simulation-based-power-analysis&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Simulation based power analysis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In part 3 you will add a simulation-based power analysis to your APA-style manuscript. While it is never advisable to calculate post-hoc power, think about this is as a future replication attempt. That is, given the current parameters (e.g., &lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(\mu M\)&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(\sigma \Sigma\)&lt;/span&gt;), if you were to replicate this study how many Ps would you need to achieve a certain level of power. Specifically, you should report a graph showing a power-curve for the design. We will discuss how to conduct simulation based power analyses in class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following should be included in the general discussion of your APA-paper (from part 2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The R code chunk conducting your power analysis (3 points)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A paragraph or two discussing and explaining your power analysis to the reader, as well as reporting the results of the power analysis. (3 points)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A graph depicting a power-curve for the design. (2 points)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A statement about how the design might be changed to achieve a desired or preferred amount of power. (2 points)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;note&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Note&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to receive full points your analysis must be reproducible. To ensure this, provide a fellow classmate with your paper and have them re-run it. If they can’t, make changes to ensure it can be reproduced by me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
